# **ORLIN ROBINSON**

IT DATA ANALYST



907-30 Ridgevalley Road Halifax, NS B3P 2J8



Call 782-414-5900



Orlin.A.T.Robinson@gmail.com



Linkedin /in/orlin-robinson

### **TECH. SKILLS**

HTML5

CCCZ

ReactJS

JS ES6

SQL | T-SQL | NOSQL - MongoDB

Linux Programming

Python Programming

Java OOF

Android Application Developmen

Tableau Desktop and Online

SAP Cloud Analytics

SAP Lumira

# TECH. AWARDS

SAFE1000 & SAFE1001 - 2018

Oracle Database 12c: Basic SOL - 2019

Oracle Database 12c: Advanced SQL - 2019

Java Fund. Orac**l**e Academy **-** 201

React JavaScript Master Package - 202

Tableau Essentials Training - 2019

Intergrating Tableau and R for Data Science - 2019

### **HOBBIES**





Working with others

Swimming

Listening to Music

Photography

#### **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

Exceptionally creative and dependable IT Analyst with a stellar customer service record and Business Analysis (BA) skills in both waterfall and agile environments. A respectful individual that promotes the engagement, uniqueness and diversity of opinion of individuals with professionalism and integrity. Highly adept at conveying complex technical information to a variety of professional and lay audiences in a clear and understandable manner, while committed to life-long learning in everything I do. Consistently demonstrates a commitment to the continuous development of Nova Scotia's economy and quality of life through education and innovation. Experienced in and receptive to an ever-changing environment, while proactively and objectively tackling problems using critical thinking skills.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

2016 - 2018

Operations Manager (Robbies Cooking Gas Refilling Plant)

Ethically collected and analyzed customer data, and used this to identify areas of opportunity and inefficiency within the company. Established methods of bridging the gap between Product Focus and Customer Delivery.

2015 - 2016

Senior HR Information Systems Analyst (Vistaprint/Cimpress)

- Administered technical and reporting support for Appraisals through SuccessFactors, providing metrics on center-wide performance and trends.
- Systems Analyst for iCIMS, and leveraged this to process the Hiring of all Employees, External Contractors, Student Interns and Expatriates.
- ${\boldsymbol \cdot}$  Systems Analyst for SAP-HR the tool used as the main hub application storing all employee data collected, from hire to termination.
- Collaborated with the Global Acquisition team, to ensure that all new acquisitions were seamlessly integrated into the Global Hierarchy, from an Organizational Unit hierarchy perspective, and a Supervisor hierarchy perspective.

2013 - 2015

HR Information Systems Analyst (Vistaprint/Cimpress)

- Monitored and processed all New Hires globally for the company, collecting data from the Recruiters and Human Resource managers, then ensuring correct entry of data into SAP. This allowed for a smooth transitioning into the company for, Active Directory creation, employee badging, IT account initializing, and the requisite systems access, all based on the nature of the New Hire's responsibilities.
- Liaised with Payroll globally for the accuracy of Pay information housed within SAP, used as the basis for which Annual and Semi-Annual merit increases were determined. Ensured that auditing data was submitted to HRIS on a pre-determined schedule, throughout all Vistaprint locations.
- Implemented Mass Change Forms and used this to liaise with Human Resource Managers across all locations, ensuring that all Position Title changes, Level Changes, Promotions, Supervisor and Department changes were all submitted to HRIS through JIRA Tickets then audited and updated in SAP in a timely manner.

# **EDUCATION**

2018 - 2020

IT Data Analytics (Nova Scotia Comm. College IT) - Two Year Diploma

Relevant Courses: SQL/NoSQL/TSQL | Business Analysis Essentials | Applied Data Analytics | Business Data Modelling

2019 - Presen

(EduNova Atlantic Canada Study and Stay  $^{\text{TM}}$  - NS ) Read more about Edunova

Selected as 1/60 NS International Students to participate in a one year Professional Development Program

# **VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE AND COMMUNITY ACTIVITIES**

9 2019 - Present

Warehouse Packer (Feed Nova Scotia)

Unpacked bulk ground produce and packaged into smaller family-sized bags

2018 - Present

Member (Jamaican Cultural Association of Nova Scotia)

 $Regularly\ attend\ association\ meetings\ and\ volunteer\ my\ services\ at\ annual\ activities\ or granised.$ 

2019 - Present

Welcome Ambassador (Nova Scotia Comm. College International Student Orientation)
Volunteered as a Welcome Ambassador to the incoming 1st year International Students on Orientation
Day